<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

 <title>Chris McComb</title>
 <link href="http://www.cmccomb.com/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
 <link href="http://www.cmccomb.com/"/>
 <updated>2019-04-13T16:34:04-04:00</updated>
 <id>http://www.cmccomb.com</id>
 <author>
   <name>Chris McComb</name>
   <email></email>
 </author>

 
 <entry>
   <title>Decision-Making In The Prescription Of Orthotics And Prosthetics For Partial-Foot Amputees</title>
   <link href="http://www.cmccomb.com/publications/2019/SaravananHippleWangMcCombMenold-DecisionMakingInThePrescription/"/>
   <updated>2019-04-01T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://www.cmccomb.com/publications/2019/SaravananHippleWangMcCombMenold-DecisionMakingInThePrescription</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Prosthetists face a daunting number of decisions that directly affect an amputee’s ability to walk and indirectly affect the overall quality of life of that amputee. In addition, the lack of resources in low-income countries provides a barrier to receive care after an amputation, and approximately 80% of amputees in low-income countries lack appropriate prosthetic care.  In this research, we are motivated to understand what factors affect the decision-making strategies of prosthetists and podiatrists when prescribing prosthetics and orthotics to partial foot amputees. This work establishes a decision-making framework as a step towards automated methods that may reduce the complexities and decision-making burden of prosthetic prescription, ultimately increasing the efficiency of prosthetic prescription in low-resourced areas. A decision-making model is proposed based on an extensive literature review of over 100 papers. The proposed model is compared to qualitative data regarding decision-making strategies during prosthetic or orthotic prescription collected from nine prosthetists, surgeons, and other healthcare professionals directly involved in amputee care. Changes to the proposed model are described and future work exploring the role of automated methods to support decision-making in the context of prosthetics is discussed.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Learning To Design From Humans: Imitating Human Designers Through Deep Learning</title>
   <link href="http://www.cmccomb.com/publications/2019/RainaMcCombCagan-LearningToDesignFromHumans/"/>
   <updated>2019-04-01T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://www.cmccomb.com/publications/2019/RainaMcCombCagan-LearningToDesignFromHumans</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Humans as designers have quite versatile problem-solving strategies. Computer agents on the other hand can access large scale computational resources to solve certain design problems. Hence, if agents can learn from human behavior, a synergetic human-agent problem solving team can be created. This paper presents an approach to extract human design strategies and implicit rules, purely from historical human data, and use that for design generation. A two-step framework that learns to imitate human design behavior from observation is proposed and implemented. This framework makes use of deep learning constructs to learn to generate designs without any explicit information about objective and performance metrics. The framework is designed to interact with the problem through a visual interface as humans did when solving the problem. It is trained to imitate a set of human designers by observing design state sequences without inducing any modelling bias or extra information about the problem. Furthermore, an end-to-end agent is developed that uses this deep learning framework as its core in conjunction with image processing to map pixel-to-design moves as a mechanism to generate designs. Finally, the designs generated by a computational team of these agents are then compared to actual human data for teams solving a truss design problem. Results demonstrates that these agents are able to create feasible and efficient truss designs without guidance, showing that this methodology allows agents to learn effective design strategies.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>On The Analysis Of A Compromised Additive Manufacturing System Using Spatio-Temporal Decomposition</title>
   <link href="http://www.cmccomb.com/publications/2019/PrakashMahanWilliamsMcCombMenoldTucker-OnTheAnalysisOfACompromised/"/>
   <updated>2019-04-01T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://www.cmccomb.com/publications/2019/PrakashMahanWilliamsMcCombMenoldTucker-OnTheAnalysisOfACompromised</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;3D printing systems have expanded the access to low cost, rapid methods for attaining physical prototypes or products. However, a cyber attack, system error, or operator error on a 3D printing system may result in catastrophic situations, ranging from complete product failure, to small types of defects which weaken the structural integrity of the product, making it unreliable for its intended use. Such defects can be introduced early-on via solid models or through G-codes for printer movements at a later stage. Previous works have studied the use of image classifiers to predict defects in real-time as a print is in progress and also by studying the printed entity once the print is complete. However, a major restriction in the functionality of these methods is the availability of a dataset capturing diverse attacks on printed entities or the printing process. This paper introduces a visual inspection technique that analyzes the  amplitude and phase variations of the print head platform arising through induced system manipulations.  The method uses an image sequence of a 3D printing process captured via an off the shelf camera to perform an offline multi-scale, multi-orientation decomposition to amplify imperceptible system movements attributable to a change in system parameters. The authors hypothesize that a change in the amplitude envelope and instantaneous phase response as a result of a change in the end effector translational instructions, to be correlated with an AM system compromise.  A case study is presented that tests the hypothesis and provides statistical validity in support of the method. The method has the potential to enhance the robustness of cyber-physical systems such as 3D printers that rely on secure, high quality hardware and software to perform optimally.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>A Comparative Study Of Virtual Reality And Computer-Aided Design To Evaluate Parts For Additive Manufacturing</title>
   <link href="http://www.cmccomb.com/publications/2019/OstranderRyanDhengreMcCombSimpsonMeisel-UserVRAndCAD/"/>
   <updated>2019-04-01T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://www.cmccomb.com/publications/2019/OstranderRyanDhengreMcCombSimpsonMeisel-UserVRAndCAD</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Virtual Reality (VR) has been shown to be an effective assistive tool in the engineering design process, aiding designers in ergonomics studies, data visualization, and manufacturing simulation. Yet there is little research exploring the advantages of VR to assist in the design for the additive manufacturing (DfAM) process. VR may present advantages over traditional computer-aided design (CAD) tools, and these advantages may be more evident as designs become more complex. The following study investigates two types of environments: 1) Immersive Virtual Reality (VR) and 2) Non-Immersive Virtual Reality (CAD) and the advantages that each environment gives to designers to assess parts for additive manufacturing. The two environments are compared to assess potential differences in DfAM decision-making. Participants familiar with DfAM are tasked with evaluating five designs of varying complexity using the Design for Additive Manufacturing Worksheet. Participant scores, evaluation times, and self-reported metrics are recorded and analyzed. Our findings indicate that as part complexity increases, DfAM scores and evaluation times increasingly differ between VR and CAD groups. We found that the VR group evaluates more complex parts at a faster rate, but with a lower accuracy when compared to the CAD group. In evaluating self-reported metrics, both groups were relatively similar; however, the CAD group reported improved confidence in identifying stress concentrations in DfAM parts. Our findings in this research identify VR as a design evaluation tool that enhances evaluation speed which speaks to its efficiency and usability; however, VR in its current form may not present the resolution necessary to identify smaller details when compared to CAD, the more accurate evaluation tool.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>The Prototyping Behaviors Of Startups: Exploring The Relationship Between Prototyping Behavior And The Financial Success Of Startups</title>
   <link href="http://www.cmccomb.com/publications/2019/NelsonMahanMcCombMenold-ThePrototypingBehaviorsOfStartups/"/>
   <updated>2019-04-01T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://www.cmccomb.com/publications/2019/NelsonMahanMcCombMenold-ThePrototypingBehaviorsOfStartups</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Prototyping is a crucial part of new product development and engineers and designers rely on prototyping to bring novel technologies to market. In recent years, tech-based startups like Tesla or Udacity have revolutionized their respective industries. However, many tech-based startups are unable to create a viable product with their available resources, and fail before ever making it to market. In this work, we analyze survey responses from 34 startup representatives to investigate the relationship between prototyping practice, startup success, and perceived difficulty of startup tasks. K-means cluster analysis shows three distinct groups, differentiated by (1) their amount of available funding, (2) their use of prototyping best practices, and (3) their reported difficulty in startup tasks. High-performing startups reported having the highest funding, experiencing less difficulty in startup tasks, and using prototyping best practices more frequently than their peers.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Assessing The Impact Of Cognitive Assistants On Mental Workload In Simple Tasks</title>
   <link href="http://www.cmccomb.com/publications/2019/MaierDonghiaChenMenoldMcComb-AssessingTheImpactOfCognitive/"/>
   <updated>2019-04-01T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://www.cmccomb.com/publications/2019/MaierDonghiaChenMenoldMcComb-AssessingTheImpactOfCognitive</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Cognitive assistants, such as Apple’s Siri or Amazon’s Alexa, are increasingly becoming routine elements of our daily lives, yet the effects of such devices on the humans using them has been largely unstudied. While much research has proposed new intelligent systems for specific contexts, few studies have characterized the dynamics between cognitive assistants and humans. In an effort to address this gap, this research study investigates the effect of cognitive assistants on mental workload. Participants perform the Wisconsin Card Sorting Task while working with a fake cognitive assistant (Mary) and concurrently completing a secondary speed and accuracy test. Performance with the cognitive assistant was found to be higher but with no significant difference in mental workload. Participants working with the cognitive assistant were found to be less frustrated than those completing the task without it.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Collaborating with Style: Using an Agent-Based Model to Simulate Cognitive Style Diversity in Problem Solving Teams</title>
   <link href="http://www.cmccomb.com/publications/2019/LappJablokowMcComb-CollaboratingWithStyle/"/>
   <updated>2019-04-01T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://www.cmccomb.com/publications/2019/LappJablokowMcComb-CollaboratingWithStyle</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Collaborative problem solving can be successful or counterproductive. The performance of collaborative teams depends not only on team members’ abilities, but also on their cognitive styles. Cognitive style measures differences in problem-solving behavior: how people generate solutions, manage structure, and interact. While teamwork and problem solving have been studied separately, their interactions are less understood. This paper introduces the KAI Agent-Based Organizational Optimization Model (KABOOM), the first model to simulate cognitive style in collaborative problem solving. KABOOM simulates the performance of teams of agents with heterogeneous cognitive styles on two contextualized design problems. Results demonstrate that, depending on the problem, certain cognitive styles may be more effective than others. Also, intentionally aligning agents’ cognitive styles with their roles can improve team performance. These experiments demonstrate that KABOOM is a useful tool for studying the effects of cognitive style on collaborative problem solving.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Evaluating Idea Quantity And Variety When Using Digital Collaboration Tools To Support Brainstorming In Non-Collocated Teams</title>
   <link href="http://www.cmccomb.com/publications/2019/KaweesaMcCombMenoldRitterMeisel-EvaluatingIdeaQuantityAndVariety/"/>
   <updated>2019-04-01T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://www.cmccomb.com/publications/2019/KaweesaMcCombMenoldRitterMeisel-EvaluatingIdeaQuantityAndVariety</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The advent of modern digital communication technology has enabled engineers to effectively collaborate regardless of team members’ geographic locations. As such, introducing engineering students to virtual environments and collaborative tools is particularly important to prepare them for careers in increasingly digital environments. This study investigates how integrating online collaboration tools in students’ idea generation activities impacts the i) quantity and ii) variety of ideas generated after a peer-feedback session. Students from five sections of a first-year engineering design course were assigned to either a collocated design team or a non-collocated design team to participate in a collaborative design feedback activity. Students individually generated an idea set using brainstorming, received peer feedback via one of two delivery conditions (in-person or virtual), and revised their idea set based on the received feedback. Each final idea set was analyzed and compared to identify any differences in the final idea quantity and variety due to the assigned feedback delivery condition. Results revealed a statistically significant difference with minimal practical significance in the final quantity of ideas and no statistically significant difference in the final variety of ideas generated between collocated and non-collocated design teams after the peer-feedback session. This suggests that feedback provided through digital tools may be used to support idea generation in non-collocated teams without being detrimental to ideation outcomes. The implications of these findings are significant for faculty or students who may be involved in online learning activities centered on engineering design.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Critical Thinking In The Design Classroom: An Analysis Of Student Design Reflections</title>
   <link href="http://www.cmccomb.com/publications/2019/EvansMenoldMcComb-CriticalThinkingInTheDesign/"/>
   <updated>2019-04-01T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://www.cmccomb.com/publications/2019/EvansMenoldMcComb-CriticalThinkingInTheDesign</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Within the domain of education, the term “critical thinking” is widely understood to mean the various skills that comprise an individual’s logical and reasoning abilities. It is critical that designers possess these abilities so that they can solve the complex problems of an increasingly interconnected world. In order to better understand patterns in engineering students’ critical thinking, this research applies the classifications of the 2001 revision of Bloom’s Taxonomy to 49 reflections written by first-year engineering students on a two-hour design practicum. Reflections were thematically coded to identify when students operated in different levels of the cognitive process and knowledge dimensions. Using k-means clustering analysis, genres of reflection were then determined. Four unique clusters of responses were identified. Notable trends in clusters included application and evaluation of procedural knowledge. Additionally, a difference was observed between the two largest clusters regarding deviance from the design process. While one cluster of responses generally minimized discussion of deviance, the second largest cluster emphasized this deviance, highlighting it as an opportunity for future growth. This work provides insight into how students learn design and how they communicate their learning, providing insight for instructors hoping to encourage deeper critical thinking in design courses.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Engineering Futures:  Updating a Successful Professional Development Program  to Address New Challenges</title>
   <link href="http://www.cmccomb.com/publications/2019/ColbryMcCombRojewskiBriliyantiColbry-EngineeringFuturesUpdatingASuccessful/"/>
   <updated>2019-04-01T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://www.cmccomb.com/publications/2019/ColbryMcCombRojewskiBriliyantiColbry-EngineeringFuturesUpdatingASuccessful</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Engineering Futures (EF) is a professional development program developed by Tau Beta Pi, the Engineering Honor Society, in the 1980s to provide undergraduate engineering students with the “soft skills” necessary for professional success. Originally, the EF program included a series of day-long, interactive workshops led by volunteer facilitators and hosted on-site at college campuses. The original sessions included People Skills (interpersonal problem communication and resolution); Team Chartering (understanding team dynamics); Group Process (tools for effective meetings); and Analytical Problem Solving (brainstorming, list reduction and evaluation criteria). Over the decades, the EF program adapted to meet the changing needs of undergraduate students, with options for shorter sessions and the addition of a module on Effective Presentation Skills in the early 2000s. In the 2010s, the EF program directors began to explore opportunities to expand the curriculum to address new challenges. A new partnership in 2015 led to the addition of two new modules: Equity, Inclusion &amp;amp; Engineering Ethics; and Research Mentoring. In 2017, Tau Beta Pi partnered with several other organizations in a successful proposal to the National Science Foundation to develop updated training materials focusing on communications, teamwork and leadership skills. These materials are being designed in a modular fashion that allows them to be adjusted for different audiences (undergraduates, graduate students, professionals) and the project includes funding for a “train the trainers” program that will enable the EF materials to be deployed nationally at little or no cost to hosting organizations. This paper provides a historical context for the EF program, describes the recent efforts to update and expand the curriculum, and provides insights from several years of participation and program evaluation data.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>A Differential Game Approach to Dynamic Competitive Decisions Toward Human-Computer Collaboration</title>
   <link href="http://www.cmccomb.com/publications/2019/BayrakMcCombCaganKotovsky-ADifferentialGameApproach/"/>
   <updated>2019-04-01T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://www.cmccomb.com/publications/2019/BayrakMcCombCaganKotovsky-ADifferentialGameApproach</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Partnership between humans and computers has a significant potential to extend the ability of humans to address complex design problems. This paper presents a decision-making process for computers to effectively collaborate with humans in the solution of complex problems under dynamic competition. In the proposed process, the computers learn strategies and objectives from prior experimental data and provide strategy suggestions to a human collaborator. The study integrates clustering and sequential learning methods from machine learning with a differential game formulation based on model predictive control to find dynamic Nash equilibrium solutions to zero-sum games. The application of the proposed approach is demonstrated on the real-time strategy game Starcraft II that offers a dynamic competitive problem comparable in complexity to real-world applications. The results show that the proposed approach can successfully identify a variety of opening strategies in the experimental data for the initial phase of the process. The game-theoretic strategies in the later phases provide useful suggestions for low-performing players but are unnecessarily conservative for high-performing players which suggest a need for human intuition to assess the value of the suggestions.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Complexity Reduction in Mass Customization To Facilitate Better Decision Support</title>
   <link href="http://www.cmccomb.com/publications/2019/BanerjeeMundaleSachcheMcComb-ComplexityReductionInMass/"/>
   <updated>2019-04-01T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://www.cmccomb.com/publications/2019/BanerjeeMundaleSachcheMcComb-ComplexityReductionInMass</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Mass customization provides a way to satisfy an increasing number of customers by tailoring product details to their preferences. Moreover, there is a considerable amount of pressure on industries that embrace mass customization in their product portfolios to consistently produce innovative and market defining technology. To ease this pressure, this study offers organizations a perspective on what combination of attributes is most influential on choice when approaching decision support for the purchase of a Configure-to-Order product. Laptops are used here as a case study, but the approach is generalizable to any family of products. This approach first uses metrics gained from a modified conjoint analysis applied to data gathered from a student consumer base. Customer satisfaction is measured as a function of how many product offerings are provided, identifying and quantifying a trade-off between customizability and consumer satisfaction. This aims to cater to the requirements of the consumer base and key business advantages allowing for greater usability and maximum profits.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Predicting Part Mass, Required Support Material, and Build Time via Autoencoded Voxel Patterns</title>
   <link href="http://www.cmccomb.com/publications/2018/MurphyMeiselSimpsonMcComb-PredictingPartMassRequired/"/>
   <updated>2018-07-01T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://www.cmccomb.com/publications/2018/MurphyMeiselSimpsonMcComb-PredictingPartMassRequired</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Additive Manufacturing (AM) allows designers to create intricate geometries that were once too complex or expensive to achieve through traditional manufacturing processes.  Currently, Design for Additive Manufacturing (DfAM) is restricted to experts in the field, and novices may overlook potentially transformational design potential enabled by AM. This project aims to make DfAM accessible to a broader audience through deep learning, enabling designers of all skill levels to leverage unique AM geometries when creating new designs.  To demonstrate such an approach, a database of files was acquired from industry-sponsored AM challenges focused on lightweight design.  These files were converted to a voxelized format, which provides more robust information for machine learning applications. Next, an autoencoder was constructed to a low-dimensional representation of the part designs.  Finally, that autoencoder was used to construct a deep neural network capable of predicting various DfAM attributes.  This work demonstrates a novel foray towards a more extensive DfAM support system that supports designers at all experience levels.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Pulling at the Digital Thread: Exploring the Tolerance Stack Up Between Automatic Procedures and Expert Strategies in Scan To Print Processes</title>
   <link href="http://www.cmccomb.com/publications/2018/MahanMeiselMcCombMenold-PullingAtTheDigital/"/>
   <updated>2018-07-01T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://www.cmccomb.com/publications/2018/MahanMeiselMcCombMenold-PullingAtTheDigital</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;While the combination of 3D scanning and printing processes holds much promise for the field of new product development, problems with repeatability and accuracy have limited the wider spread adoption of 3D scan to print processes. Some studies have explored the errors inherent in higher fidelity scan to print (S2P) processes, yet few have explored the errors in S2P processes that leverage affordable rapid non-contact digitizers. No studies have explored the strategies experts in digital fabrication employ to mitigate geometric and dimensional errors throughout the S2P process. To address these gaps, a controlled study was conducted using data from 27 scans collected with a common off-the-shelf non-contact optical digitizer and a relatively simple workpiece. Additionally, a behavioral study was conducted with 13 experts in digital fabrication; actions were recorded and later analyzed using hidden Markov modeling. The geometric and dimensional integrity of the digital models was found to be significantly out of tolerance at various phases of the S2P process, as compared to the truth model. Larger errors were found more consistently in the beginning of the S2P process, but these errors were not sufficiently filtered out during the remainder of the process. Experts strategies were not beneficial and digital models produced by experts were found to be significantly smaller than truth models, indicating a trend to “over-clean” digital models. Our findings imply that designers leveraging off-the-shelf RE tools may encounter significant barriers when attempting to integrate digitization tools into the design process.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Expanding the Solution Space in Engineering Design Education: A Simulation-Based Investigation of Product Dissection</title>
   <link href="http://www.cmccomb.com/publications/2018/AlzayedMcCombHunterMiller-HelpingTeamsExpandThe/"/>
   <updated>2018-07-01T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://www.cmccomb.com/publications/2018/AlzayedMcCombHunterMiller-HelpingTeamsExpandThe</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Product dissection has been highlighted as an effective means of interacting with example products in order to produce creative outcomes. While product dissection is often conducted as a team in engineering design education, the research on the effectiveness of product dissection activities has been primarily limited to individuals. Thus, the goal of this study was to investigate the impact of the type(s) of product dissected in a team environment on the breadth of the design space explored and the underlying influence of educational level and dissection modality on these effects. This was accomplished through a computational simulation of 14,000 nominal brainstorming teams generated by a statistical bootstrapping technique that accounted for all possible team configurations. Specifically, each team was composed of four team members based on a design repository of 931 ideas generated by first-year and senior engineering design students after a product dissection activity. The results of the study highlight that educational level, dissection modality and the number of products dissected all significantly impacted the solution space explored by the simulated teams. Specifically, senior engineering students, physically dissecting the product, and dissecting a wider variety of products all positively impacted the solution space explored. However, several interactions drove further differences. The findings presented in this study can lead to a better understanding of how to most effectively deploy product dissection modules in engineering design education in order to maximize the solution space explored.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Opportunities for Natural Language Processing in Qualitative Engineering Education Research: Two Examples</title>
   <link href="http://www.cmccomb.com/publications/2018/BerdanierBakerWangMcComb-OpportunitiesForNaturalLanguage/"/>
   <updated>2018-06-01T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://www.cmccomb.com/publications/2018/BerdanierBakerWangMcComb-OpportunitiesForNaturalLanguage</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;This research full paper proposes opportunities to expand qualitative and textual data analysis using natural language processing (NLP), and demonstrates opportunities to use NLP in engineering education work in our presentation of two NLP-based projects as examples of how NLP can be used. The discipline of engineering education frequently employs qualitative data analysis techniques, but fundamentally, the analysis of large corpora of textual documents is limited by researcher’s time. In this paper, we present a brief review literature of how NLP has been used in other qualitative research fields. This portion of the paper is aimed to provide a clear description of NLP for those unfamiliar with machine learning and natural language processing methods. The second part of the paper will provide two brief examples of how NLP is being employed in our research group. Example 1 is a study of engineering résumés, with the intention of being able to calculate the “disciplinary discourse density” based off the engineering language presented in engineering résumés, a technique validated in prior qualitative studies by hand. Example 2 is a genre analysis of engineering literature reviews, seeking to understand the ways in which sentences linguistically build into arguments, such that the task of writing literature reviews might be demystified. This paper will have a methodological impact for researchers attempting to use NLP methods to analyze qualitative data, articulating the opportunities and barriers in using these methods for engineering education research.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Design Practica as Authentic Assessments in First-year Engineering Design Courses</title>
   <link href="http://www.cmccomb.com/publications/2018/McCombBerdanierMenold-DesignPracticaAsAuthentic/"/>
   <updated>2018-05-15T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://www.cmccomb.com/publications/2018/McCombBerdanierMenold-DesignPracticaAsAuthentic</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;This paper describes the design and evaluation of a novel assessment for first-year engineering design courses that is rooted in an authentic design challenge. This approach modifies the traditional written-exam approach typically found in engineering courses, which is inherently inauthentic and cannot easily capture the exploratory nature of engineering design. Our assessment improves alignment with common learning objectives found in first-year engineering design courses and additionally prepares students for the type of case study interviews that are increasingly common for entry-level engineering jobs. To evaluate our assessment, 50 first-year students completed the engineering design self-efficacy instrument once before beginning the assessment and a second time approximately 48 hours later upon completion of a reflection assignment. In addition, students retrospectively reported their perceived change in self-efficacy during the assessment. Analysis shows that students perceived a large retrospective increase in skill level, despite only a small increase in directly measured self-efficacy. These results are analyzed in light of the Dunning-Kruger effect and we posit that the assessment helps to align students’ self-efficacy with their actual skill level. Increased alignment of self-efficacy with skill level may minimize student frustration when encountering challenging tasks in the future, potentially increasing retention of engineering students as well as facilitating the development of lifelong learning attitudes.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Are Teams Teams? And Other Musings on Humpty Dumpty&rsquo;s Use of Language In The Design World</title>
   <link href="http://www.cmccomb.com/publications/2018/KotovskyCaganMcComb-HumptyDumptysUseOf/"/>
   <updated>2018-05-01T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://www.cmccomb.com/publications/2018/KotovskyCaganMcComb-HumptyDumptysUseOf</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;This extended abstract explores fundamental assumptions of engineering design methodology and theory that are called into question by recent work. This piece is centered around four questions that highlight the assumptions that we explore. These are (1) Are teams teams? (2) Is search good? (3) Are analogies analogous? and (4) Is novelty novel? Our intent is to generate critical discourse around these topics and encourage the community to continue to challenge underlying assumptions.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Design Strategy Transfer in Cognitively-Inspired Agents</title>
   <link href="http://www.cmccomb.com/publications/2018/RainaMcCombCagan-DesignStrategyTransferIn/"/>
   <updated>2018-04-15T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://www.cmccomb.com/publications/2018/RainaMcCombCagan-DesignStrategyTransferIn</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Planning and strategizing is an essential part of the design process based on the designer’s skill. Further, planning is an abstract skill that can be transferred between similar problems. However, planning and strategy transfer within design has not been effectively modeled within computational agents. This paper presents an approach to represent this strategizing behavior in a probabilistic model. This model is employed to select the operations that computational agents should perform while solving configuration design tasks. This work also demonstrates that this probabilistic model can be used to transfer strategies from human data to computational agents in a way that is general and useful. This study shows a successful transfer of design strategy from human-to-computer agents, opening up the possibility of deriving high-performing behavior from designers and using it to guide computational design agents. Finally, quintessential behavior of transfer learning is illustrated by agents while transferring design strategies across different problems, improving agent performance significantly. The work presented in this study leverages a computational framework built by embedding cognitive characteristics into agents, which has shown to mimic human problem solving in configuration design problems.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>A Two-Tiered Grammatical Approach For Agent-Based Computational Design</title>
   <link href="http://www.cmccomb.com/publications/2018/PuentesMcCombCagan-ATwoTieredGrammatical/"/>
   <updated>2018-04-15T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://www.cmccomb.com/publications/2018/PuentesMcCombCagan-ATwoTieredGrammatical</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Early stages of the engineering design process are vital to shaping the final design; each subsequent step builds from the initial concept. Innovation-driven engineering problems require designers to focus heavily on early-stage design generation, with constant application and evaluation of design changes. Strategies to reduce the amount of time and effort designers spend in this phase could improve the efficiency of the design process as a whole. This paper seeks to create and demonstrate a two-tiered design grammar that encodes heuristic strategies to aid in the generation of early solution concepts. Specifically, this two-tiered grammar mimics the combination of heuristic-based strategic actions and parametric modifications employed by human designers. Rules in the higher-tier are abstract and potentially applicable to multiple design problems across a number of fields. These abstract rules are translated into a series of lower-tier rule applications in a spatial design grammar, which are inherently domain-specific. This grammar is implemented within the HSAT agent-based algorithm. Agents iteratively select actions from either the higher-tier or lower-tier. This algorithm is applied to the design of wave energy converters, devices which use the motion of ocean waves to generate electrical power. Comparisons are made between designs generated using only lower-tier rules and those generated using only higher-tier rules.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>"Thus, I had to go with what I had": A Multiple Methods Exploration of Novice Designers Articulation of Prototyping Decisions
</title>
   <link href="http://www.cmccomb.com/publications/2018/MenoldBerdanierMcCombHockerGardner-ThusIHadTo/"/>
   <updated>2018-04-15T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://www.cmccomb.com/publications/2018/MenoldBerdanierMcCombHockerGardner-ThusIHadTo</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Effectively communicating designs to stakeholders or end users is a critical step in the design process yet can be a difficult challenge for engineers. Prototypes are unique tools that can enhance communication between these two groups, as prototypes are physical manifestations of the designer’s mental model. Previous work has demonstrated that novice designers often struggle to use prototypes as communication tools. We argue that it is critical that engineering students learn to fully leverage prototypes, and thus the current work sought to understand the relationship between argumentation, prototyping, and design decisions. In order to understand the communication patterns of novice designers during a prototyping task, a controlled study was conducted with a total of 46 undergraduate engineering students. The analysis of quantitative and qualitative data point to the intricate linkages between how students make material decisions and how they justify those decisions.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Designing Improved Teams for Crowdsourced Competitions</title>
   <link href="http://www.cmccomb.com/publications/2018/McCombMaier-DesigningImprovedTeamsFor/"/>
   <updated>2018-04-15T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://www.cmccomb.com/publications/2018/McCombMaier-DesigningImprovedTeamsFor</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Teams are ubiquitous, woven into the fabric of engineering and design. Often, it is assumed that teams are better at solving problems than individuals working independently. Recent work in engineering, design, and psychology has indicated that teams may not be the problem-solving panacea that they were once thought to be. Crowdsourcing has seen increased interest in engineering design recently, and platforms often encourage teamwork between participants. This work undertakes an analysis of the performance of different team styles and sizes in crowdsourced competitions. This work demonstrates that groups of individuals working independently may outperform interacting teams on average, but that small interacting teams are more likely to win competitions. These results are discussed in the context of motivation for crowdsourcing participants.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Helping Teams Expand the Breadth of Their Solution Space Through Product Dissection: A Simulation Based Investigation</title>
   <link href="http://www.cmccomb.com/publications/2018/AlzayedMcCombHunterMiller-HelpingTeamsExpandThe/"/>
   <updated>2018-04-15T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://www.cmccomb.com/publications/2018/AlzayedMcCombHunterMiller-HelpingTeamsExpandThe</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Product dissection has been highlighted as an effective means of interacting with example products in order to produce creative outcomes. While product dissection is often conducted as a team in engineering design education as a component of larger engineering design projects (e.g. cornerstone and capstone design), the research on the effectiveness of product dissection activities has been primarily limited to individuals. Thus, the goal of this study was to investigate the impact of the type(s) of product dissected in a team environment on the breadth of the design space explored and the underlying influence of educational level on these effects. This was accomplished through a computational simulation of 7,000 nominal brainstorming teams composed of four team members based on a design repository of 463 ideas generated by first-year and senior engineering design students after a product dissection activity. The results of the study highlight that simulated senior engineering design teams explored a larger solution space than first-year teams and that dissecting different types of products allowed for the exploration of a larger solution space for all of the simulated teams. The results also showed that dissecting two analogically far products and two simple products was most effective in expanding the solution space of simulated senior engineering design teams, but this was not necessarily the case for first-year teams. The findings presented in this study can lead to a better understanding of how to most effectively deploy product dissection modules in engineering design education in order to maximize the solution space explored by nominal brainstorming teams.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Data on the Design of Truss Structures by Teams of Engineering Students</title>
   <link href="http://www.cmccomb.com/publications/2018/McCombCaganKotovsky-DataOnTheDesign/"/>
   <updated>2018-02-01T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://www.cmccomb.com/publications/2018/McCombCaganKotovsky-DataOnTheDesign</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;This experiment was conducted in order to compare different approaches that human teams use to solve design problems that change dynamically during solving. Specifically, study participants were given the task of designing a truss structure (similar to a bridge spanning a chasm) in teams of three. At two points during design, the problem statement was changed unexpectedly, requiring participants to adapt. Two conditions were given different initial problem representations. During the study, every participant had access to a computer interface that allowed them to construct, test, and share solutions. The interface also made it possible to collect a step-by-step log of the actions made by participants during the study. This article contains data collected from 48 participants (16 teams). This data has been used previously in behavioral analyses, sequence-based analysis, and development of computational models.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Multi-Objective Optimization and Scenario-based Robustness Analysis of the Moneymaker Hip Pump</title>
   <link href="http://www.cmccomb.com/publications/2018/McCombetal-MultiObjectiveOptimization/"/>
   <updated>2018-01-01T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://www.cmccomb.com/publications/2018/McCombetal-MultiObjectiveOptimization</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Water-lifting technologies for irrigation have significant potential to increase agricultural yields and stimulate economic growth in rural areas of the developing world. Human-powered water pumps have been used with great success in this rapidly developing market. KickStart’s MoneyMaker Hip Pump is a human-powered water pump with additional design features that make it lightweight and portable for use in remote fields in several countries throughout Africa. This work first applied numerical optimization techniques to the design of the MoneyMaker Hip Pump and offers further improvements to its design. Deterministic multi-objective optimization methods were employed to maximize the flow rate of the pump, maximize the pumping height of water, and minimize cost. Following optimization, the robustness of the optimized pump design was analyzed under several modified scenarios, including fouling of the hoses and a decrease in operator power due to fatigue or aging. The set of cost-optimized pump designs was then compared to a second set of optimal designs that was found using material volume as a simplified proxy for the cost objective function. Findings indicate that several technical improvements can be made to the current MoneyMaker Hip Pump design to reduce cost by up to 37% without affecting water flow rate, or increase water flow rate by up to 88% without increasing cost. The numerical model was validated through physical experimentation of the MoneyMaker Hip Pump, and design alterations to reduce cost were experimentally shown to maintain pump performance.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Towards the Rapid Design of Engineered Systems Through Deep Neural Networks</title>
   <link href="http://www.cmccomb.com/publications/2017/McComb-TowardsRapidDesignOf/"/>
   <updated>2017-12-01T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://www.cmccomb.com/publications/2017/McComb-TowardsRapidDesignOf</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The design of a system commits a significant portion of the final cost of that system. Many computational approaches have been developed to assist designers in the analysis (e.g., computational fluid dynamics) and synthesis (e.g., topology optimization) of engineered systems. However, many of these approaches are computationally intensive, taking significant time to complete an analysis and even longer to iteratively synthesize a solution. The current work proposes a methodology for rapidly evaluating and synthesizing engineered systems through the use of deep neural networks. The proposed methodology is applied to the analysis and synthesis of offshore structures such as oil platforms. These structures are constructed in a marine environment and are typically designed to achieve specific dynamics in response to a known spectrum of ocean waves. Results show that deep learning can be used to accurately and rapidly synthesize and analyze off- shore structure.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Application of Project-based Learning within the Context of Sustainable Development in Education of International Engineer Citizens</title>
   <link href="http://www.cmccomb.com/publications/2017/TehraniMcCombPapavasiliou-ApplicationOfProjectBased/"/>
   <updated>2017-11-01T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://www.cmccomb.com/publications/2017/TehraniMcCombPapavasiliou-ApplicationOfProjectBased</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;This paper outlines a project-based learning approach to engineering education. This approach directly employs sustainable development as a vehicle to prepare students for global engineering challenges. The theoretical concept of the presented work utilizes the extended situational teaching model. This model explains the role of the teacher-leader in engineering classroom to help students with gaining essential elements of engineering education, including superior knowledge, reliable skills, and professional attitude. Case studies and examples of experiential learning projects demonstrate the development of links between classroom teaching, research advising, laboratory works, and field projects, including both domestic and international projects.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Data on the Configuration Design of Internet-Connected Home Cooling Systems by Engineering Students</title>
   <link href="http://www.cmccomb.com/publications/2017/McCombCaganKotovsky-DataOnTheConfiguration/"/>
   <updated>2017-09-04T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://www.cmccomb.com/publications/2017/McCombCaganKotovsky-DataOnTheConfiguration</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;This experiment was carried out to record the step-by-step actions that humans take in solving a configuration design problem, either in small teams or individually. Specifically, study participants were tasked with configuring an internet-connected system of products to maintain temperature within a home, subject to cost constraints. Every participant was given access to a computer-based design interface that allowed them to construct and assess solutions. The interface was also used to record the data that is presented here. In total, data was collected for 68 participants, and each participant was allowed to perform 50 design actions in solving the configuration design problem. Major results based on the data presented here have been reported separately, including initial behavioral analysis and design pattern assessments via Markovian modeling.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Validating a Tool for Predicting Problem-Specific Optimized Team Characteristics</title>
   <link href="http://www.cmccomb.com/publications/2017/McCombCaganKotovsky-ValidatingAToolFor/"/>
   <updated>2017-08-09T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://www.cmccomb.com/publications/2017/McCombCaganKotovsky-ValidatingAToolFor</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The performance of a team is highly dependent on how the team is structured, how individuals in the team communicate with one another, and the properties exhibited by the problem being solved. It is generally assumed that teams are a superior approach in problem-solving and design. However, this work shows that for a configuration design problem of moderate size, the optimal approach for a homogenous team is in fact for members of the team to work independently, with the best solution from the individuals chosen at the end. Moreover, this work demonstrates that this surprising strategy can be predicted from knowledge of the problem’s properties through a computationally-derived set of response surfaces. First, a novel design problem is defined that requires solvers to create a system of internet-connected products to maintain the temperature within a home. Next, the characteristics of this new design problem are measured, and a computationally-derived response surface yields the untraditional prediction that teams should not interact while solving the problem. Finally, this prediction is tested and shown correct through a cognitive study. This work makes two contributions to the state of the art. First, it provides verification of a methodology that allows optimal team characteristics to be predicted based on knowledge of a design problem. Second, it demonstrates an additional problem instance for which interacting teams are inferior to nominal teams (adding to a growing literature to that effect).&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Ethical Design of Gendered Products</title>
   <link href="http://www.cmccomb.com/publications/2017/RoyMcComb-EthicalDesignOfGendered/"/>
   <updated>2017-07-01T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://www.cmccomb.com/publications/2017/RoyMcComb-EthicalDesignOfGendered</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Engineers and marketers often design products for specific genders in order to segment the market. Sometimes ergonomics and function determine the perceived gender of a product, but often it is arbitrary. Research in gender studies shows us that these arbitrarily gendered products force consumers into gender roles and support stereotypes of femininity and masculinity. Within this context, the workshop will ask conference attendees to consider the following questions: Who is ethically responsible for the creation and consumption of products? How can engineers and designers create more inclusive designs? The goal of this workshop is to provide a forum for discussing the cultural and ethical implications of gendered products and to provide participants with an opportunity to engage firsthand in the process of designing ethically gendered products. The workshop will be delivered in a way that is accessible for both technical and non-technical conference attendees.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Eliciting Configuration Design Heuristics with Hidden Markov Models</title>
   <link href="http://www.cmccomb.com/publications/2017/McCombCaganKotovsky-ElicitingConfigurationDesignHeuristics/"/>
   <updated>2017-07-01T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://www.cmccomb.com/publications/2017/McCombCaganKotovsky-ElicitingConfigurationDesignHeuristics</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Configuration design problems, characterized by the selection and assembly of components into a final desired solution, are common in engineering design. Although a variety of theoretical approaches to solving configuration design problems have been developed, little research has been conducted to observe how humans naturally attempt to solve such problems. This work mines the data from a cognitive study of configuration design to extract helpful design heuristics. The extraction of these heuristics is automated through the application of hidden Markov models. Results show that, for a truss configuration problem, designers proceed through four procedural states in solving configuration design problems, transitioning from topology design to shape and parameter design. High-performing designers are distinguished by their opportunistic tuning of parameters early in the process, enabling a heuristic search process similar to the A* search algorithm.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Mining Process Heuristics from Designer Action Data via Hidden Markov Models</title>
   <link href="http://www.cmccomb.com/publications/2017/McCombCaganKotovsky-MiningProcessHeuristics/"/>
   <updated>2017-05-01T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://www.cmccomb.com/publications/2017/McCombCaganKotovsky-MiningProcessHeuristics</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Configuration design problems, characterized by the assembly of components into a final desired solution, are common in engineering design. Various theoretical approaches have been offered for solving configuration type problems, but few studies have examined the approach that humans naturally use to solve such problems. This work applies data-mining techniques to quantitatively study the processes that designers use to solve configuration design problems. The guiding goal is to extract beneficial design process heuristics that are generalizable to the entire class of problems. The extraction of these human problem-solving heuristics is automated through the application of hidden Markov models to the data from two behavioral studies. Results show that designers proceed through four procedural states in solving configuration design problems, roughly transitioning from topology design to shape and parameter design. High-performing designers are distinguished by their opportunistic tuning of parameters early in the process, enabling a more effective and nuanced search for solutions.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Capturing Human Sequence-Learning Abilities in Configuration Design Tasks through Markov Chains</title>
   <link href="http://www.cmccomb.com/publications/2017/McCombCaganKotovsky-CapturingHumanSequenceLearning/"/>
   <updated>2017-05-01T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://www.cmccomb.com/publications/2017/McCombCaganKotovsky-CapturingHumanSequenceLearning</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Designers often search for new solutions by iteratively adapting a current design. By engaging in this search, designers not only improve solution quality but also begin to learn what operational patterns might improve the solution in future iterations. Previous work in psychology has demonstrated that humans can fluently and adeptly learn short operational sequences that aid problem-solving. This paper explores how designers learn and employ sequences within the realm of engineering design. Specifically, this work analyzes behavioral patterns in two human studies in which participants solved configuration design problems. Behavioral data from the two studies is first analyzed using Markov chains to determine how much representation complexity is necessary to quantify the sequential patterns that designers employ during solving. It is discovered that first-order Markov chains are capable of accurately representing designers’ sequences. Next, the ability to learn first-order sequences is implemented in an agent-based modeling framework to assess the performance implications of sequence-learning abilities. These computational studies confirm the assumption that the ability to learn sequences is beneficial to designers.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Impossible by Design? Fairness, Strategy, and Arrow's Impossibility Theorem</title>
   <link href="http://www.cmccomb.com/publications/2017/McCombGoucherLamberCagan-ImpossibleByDesign/"/>
   <updated>2017-02-01T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://www.cmccomb.com/publications/2017/McCombGoucherLamberCagan-ImpossibleByDesign</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The design process often requires work by teams, rather than individuals. During team based design it is likely that situations will arise in which individual members of the team have different opinions, yet a group decision must still be made. Unfortunately, Arrow’s impossibility theorem indicates that there is no method for aggregating group preferences that will always satisfy a small number of ‘fair’ conditions. This work seeks to identify methods of combining individual preferences that can come close to satisfying Arrow’s conditions, enabling decisions that are fairer in practice. First, experiential conjoint analysis was used to obtain individual empirical utility functions for drinking mug designs. Each empirical utility function represented individual members who were part of a design team. Then, a number of functions for constructing group preference were analysed using both randomly generated preferences and empirical preferences derived from the experiential conjoint survey. The analysis involved checking each of Arrow’s conditions, as well as assessing the potential impact of strategic voting. Based on the results, methods that should be used to aggregate group preference within a design team in practice were identified and recommended.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Optimizing Design Teams Based on Problem Properties: Computational Team Simulations and an Applied Empirical Test</title>
   <link href="http://www.cmccomb.com/publications/2017/McCombCaganKotovsky-OptimizingDesignTeams/"/>
   <updated>2017-02-01T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://www.cmccomb.com/publications/2017/McCombCaganKotovsky-OptimizingDesignTeams</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The performance of a team with the right characteristics can exceed the mere sum of the constituent members’ individual efforts. However, a team having the wrong characteristics may perform more poorly than the sum of its individuals. Therefore, it is vital that teams are assembled and managed properly in order to maximize performance. This work examines how the properties of configuration design problems can be leveraged to select the best values for team characteristics (specifically team size and interaction frequency). A computational model of design teams which has been shown to effectively emulate human team behavior is employed to pinpoint optimized team characteristics for solving a variety of configuration design problems. These configuration design problems are characterized with respect to the local and global structure of the design space, the alignment between objectives, and the resources allotted for solving the problem. Regression analysis is then used to create equations for predicting optimized values for team characteristics based on problem properties. These equations achieve moderate to high accuracy, making it possible to design teams based on those problem properties. Further analysis reveals hypotheses about how the problem properties can influence a team’s search for solutions. This work also conducts a cognitive study on a different problem to test the predictive equations. For a configuration problem of moderate size, the model predicts that zero interaction between team members should lead to the best outcome. A cognitive study of human teams verifies this surprising prediction, offering partial validation of the predictive theory.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Designing the Characteristics of Design Teams via Cognitively Inspired Computational Modeling</title>
   <link href="http://www.cmccomb.com/publications/2016/McComb-DesignTheCharacteristicsOf/"/>
   <updated>2016-08-01T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://www.cmccomb.com/publications/2016/McComb-DesignTheCharacteristicsOf</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Teams are a ubiquitous part of the design process and a great deal of time and effort is devoted to managing them effectively. Although teams have the potential to search effectively for solutions, they are also prone to a number of pitfalls. Thus, a greater understanding of teams is necessary to ensure that they can function optimally across a variety of tasks. Teams are typically studied through controlled laboratory experiments or through longitudinal studies that observe teams in situ. However, both of these study types can be costly and time-consuming. Months, if not years, pass between the initial conception of a study and the final analysis of results. This work creates a computational framework that efficiently emulates human design teams, thus facilitating the derivation of a theory linking the properties of design problems to optimized team characteristics, effectively making it possible to design design teams. This dissertation first introduces and validates the Cognitively-Inspired Simulated Annealing Teams (CISAT) modeling framework. The central structure of CISAT is modeled after simulated annealing, a global optimization algorithm that has been shown to effectively mimic the problem-solving process of individuals. Specifically, a multi-agent analog of simulated annealing is used in CISAT to mimic the behavior of teams. Several additional components, drawn from the psychology and problem-solving literature, are then included in the framework to enable a more accurate description of individual activity and interaction within the team. CISAT is then used to investigate the relationship between design problem properties, team characteristics, and task performance. Multiple computational simulations are conducted in which simulated teams with various characteristics solve a variety of different configuration problems. These simulations are then post-processed to produce a set of equations that make it possible to predict optimal team characteristics based on problem properties, thus enabling the optimal design of design teams. To validate these equations a behavioral study is designed and conducted in which teams of engineering students interact at different frequencies while designing a complex system. Results of the study offer a limited validation of the predictive equations. This dissertation further highlights the resource efficiency and versatility of CISAT by demonstrating its use in two additional applications. In the first, a new numerical optimization algorithm is derived directly from CISAT by stripping away all but the most quintessential team-based characteristics. The team-based characteristics of this algorithm allow it to achieve high performance across a variety of objective function with diverse topographies. In the second application, CISAT is used in conjunction with Markov concepts to examine the order in which designers make changes to their solutions. Although it has been demonstrated that humans apply changes in a specific order (called a sequence) when solving puzzles, such patterns have not been examined for engineers solving design problems. It is shown that operation sequences are used by designers, and improve solution quality. This dissertation demonstrates how characteristics of individual designers and design teams can be captured and accurately reproduced within a computational model to advance our knowledge of design methodology. Future extensions of this work have the potential to inform a deeper and more holistic understanding of the search process.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Scenario-Based Robustness Analysis of Optimized I.D.E.-Style Treadle Pump Designs</title>
   <link href="http://www.cmccomb.com/publications/2016/McCombJohnsonGorman-ScenarioBasedRobustnessAnalysis/"/>
   <updated>2016-01-01T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://www.cmccomb.com/publications/2016/McCombJohnsonGorman-ScenarioBasedRobustnessAnalysis</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Poverty affects hundreds of millions of people globally. Market-based strategies can help alleviate poverty in developing countries by encouraging entrepreneurial activity and have the potential to be more effective than traditional approaches, such as development aid from countries or non-governmental organizations. Development organizations often target the agricultural sector because of the prevalence of subsistence and small-scale farming, particularly in rural regions of developing countries. Improving the reliability of irrigation techniques can help farmers expand out of primarily subsistence farming and begin to sell a portion of their crop, thus achieving the objectives of market-based poverty alleviation. Human-powered pumps are a popular tool used in irrigation because they require low capital cost and negligible operating cost. Previous work provided a model for finding Pareto-optimal IDE-style treadle pump designs. This work utilizes that model to produce a dense set of Pareto-optimal designs, and then investigates the robustness of the designs by simulating their performance in a variety of modified use scenarios. Our results show that pumps optimized for low flow rates (less than 3.0 L/s) are highly robust, particularly with respect to age-related changes in the operator’s stature or mobility. In addition, these pumps can operate with near-optimal efficiency across a variety of target flow rates and well depths. These pumps are ideal for single family use or for shared use amongst multiple families in a village. Pumps optimized for flow rates greater than 3.0 L/s are less robust with respect to changes of operator stature (experiencing decreases in flow rate of up to 60%) but may be suitable for use on farms or by service providers.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Utilizing Markov Chains to Understand Operation Sequencing in Design Tasks</title>
   <link href="http://www.cmccomb.com/publications/2016/McCombCaganKotovsky-UtilizingMarkovChains/"/>
   <updated>2016-01-01T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://www.cmccomb.com/publications/2016/McCombCaganKotovsky-UtilizingMarkovChains</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Design often involves searching for a final design solution by iteratively modifying and adjusting a current design. Through this process designers are able to improve the quality of the current design and also learn what patterns of operations are most likely to lead to the quickest future improvements. Prior work in psychology has shown that humans can be adept at learning how to apply short sequences of operations for maximum effect while solving a problem. This work explores the sequencing of operations specifically within the domain of engineering design by examining the results of a human study in which participants designed trusses. A statistical analysis of the data from that study uses Markov Chains to show with high confidence that meaningful operation sequences exist. This work also uses an agent-based modeling framework in conjunction with Markov Chain concepts to simulate the performance of teams with and without the ability to learn sequences. These computational studies offer confirmation for the conclusion that sequence-learning abilities are helpful during design.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Linking Properties of Design Problems to Optimal Team Characteristics</title>
   <link href="http://www.cmccomb.com/publications/2016/McCombCaganKotovsky-LinkingPropertiesOfDesign/"/>
   <updated>2016-01-01T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://www.cmccomb.com/publications/2016/McCombCaganKotovsky-LinkingPropertiesOfDesign</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;A team with the right characteristics can exceed the sum of their individual efforts. However, a team having the wrong characteristics may perform more poorly than the sum of its individuals. Therefore, it is crucial that teams are assembled and managed properly in order to maximize performance. This work examines how the properties of a design problem can be used to select the best values for team characteristics. Two characteristics are considered: team size and interaction frequency. A computational model of design teams that has been shown to effectively emulate human team behavior is leveraged to pinpoint optimized team characteristics for solving a variety of fluid and structural design problems. The nature of each design problem is characterized with respect to local and global behavior of the design space, alignment between objective functions, and the resources allotted for solving the problem. Regression analysis is used to create equations for predicting optimized team characteristics based on problem properties. These equations, which enable the informed design of design teams based on those characteristics, describe statistically significant relationships and are found to have useful levels of accuracy. Further analysis reveals insights about how the properties of a design problem can influence a team’s search for solutions.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Drawing Inspiration From Human Design Teams for Better Search and Optimization: The Heterogeneous Simulated Annealing Teams Algorithm</title>
   <link href="http://www.cmccomb.com/publications/2016/McCombCaganKotovsky-DrawingInspirationFromHuman/"/>
   <updated>2016-01-01T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://www.cmccomb.com/publications/2016/McCombCaganKotovsky-DrawingInspirationFromHuman</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Insights uncovered by research in design cognition are often utilized to develop methods used by human designers; in this work, such insights are used to inform and improve computational methodologies. This paper introduces the heterogeneous simulated annealing team (HSAT) algorithm, a multiagent simulated annealing (MSA) algorithm. HSAT is based on a validated computational model of human-based engineering design and retains characteristics of the model that structure interaction between team members and allow for heterogeneous search strategies to be employed within a team. The performance of this new algorithm is compared to several other simulated annealing (SA) based algorithms on three carefully selected benchmarking functions. The HSAT algorithm provides terminal solutions that are better on average than other algorithms explored in this work.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Fairness and Manipulation: An Empirical Study of Arrow’s Impossibility Theorem International Conference on Engineering Design</title>
   <link href="http://www.cmccomb.com/publications/2015/McCombGoucherLambertCagan-FairnessAndManipulation/"/>
   <updated>2015-07-01T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://www.cmccomb.com/publications/2015/McCombGoucherLambertCagan-FairnessAndManipulation</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The design process often requires work by teams, rather than individuals. During these times it is likely that situations will arise in which members of a team have different opinions, yet a group decision must still be made. Unfortunately, Arrow’s Impossibility Theorem indicates that there is no method for aggregating group preferences that will always satisfy a small number of “fair” conditions. This work seeks to identify methods of combining individual preferences that can come close to satisfying Arrow’s conditions. Experiential conjoint analysis was used to obtain empirical utility functions for drinking mug designs. A number of functions for constructing group preference were then analysed using both empirical conjoint preferences and randomly generated preferences. This analysis involved checking each of Arrow’s conditions, as well as computing the likelihood that a method will be susceptible to manipulation by a dishonest individual. Based on the results, methods that should be used to aggregate group preference in practice are recommended.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Heterogeneous Simulated Annealing Teams: An Optimizing Search Algorithm Inspired by Engineering Design Teams</title>
   <link href="http://www.cmccomb.com/publications/2015/McCombCaganKotovsky-HeterogeneousSimulatedAnnealingTeams/"/>
   <updated>2015-07-01T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://www.cmccomb.com/publications/2015/McCombCaganKotovsky-HeterogeneousSimulatedAnnealingTeams</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Although insights uncovered by design cognition are often utilized to develop the methods used by human designers, using such insights to inform computational methodologies also has the potential to improve the performance of design algorithms. This paper uses insights from research on design cognition and design teams to inform a better simulated annealing search algorithm. Simulated annealing has already been established as a model of individual problem solving. This paper introduces the Heterogeneous Simulated Annealing Team (HSAT) algorithm, a multi-agent simulated annealing algorithm. Each agent controls an adaptive annealing schedule, allowing the team develop heterogeneous search strategies. Such diversity is a natural part of engineering design, and boosts performance in other multi-agent algorithms. Further, interaction between agents in HSAT is structured to mimic interaction between members of a design team. Performance is compared to several other simulated annealing algorithms, a random search algorithm, and a gradient-based algorithm. Compared to other algorithms, the team-based HSAT algorithm returns better average results with lower variance.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>The Cyborg Designer</title>
   <link href="http://www.cmccomb.com/publications/2015/McComb-TheCyborgDesigner/"/>
   <updated>2015-07-01T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://www.cmccomb.com/publications/2015/McComb-TheCyborgDesigner</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Designers perform phenomenally well in tasks that involve creativity and insight - tasks that are typically unfeasible for design algorithms. However, design algorithms excel at tasks that are tedious and time-consuming for human designers, such as searching graphs, accessing and parsing large amounts of information, and optimizing mathematical functions. This complementary relationship is typically exploited by providing designers with computational tools that can be accessed at will. However, designers tend to become “set in their ways”, relying heavily on previous solutions and well-known methods. This is especially true of expert designers and can hinder the adoption of new computational tools, leading to potentially non-optimal solutions. I will outline my vision for a future in which human designers are seamlessly connected with computational design agents, thus becoming part of a cyborg design system. My current research creates multi-agent design algorithms that may eventually form the backbone of such a system. In much the same way that robots resemble humans to operate efficiently in human-centric environments, computational design agents must be capable of interfacing with the design ecosystem as human designers do. As agents parse emails and design specifications, listen to conversations, and make sense of photographs and sketches they will not only be learning about the current design project, but learning the preferences of the designers that they work with. Based on this data agents can perform a host of support tasks, such as providing relevant analogies for consideration, recommending technical modifications to designs, and suggesting aesthetic design improvements that are aligned with a designer’s personal style. Although computational design agents will exist as cloud computing artifacts, they will monitor and interface with designers through a variety of wearable, mobile, and desktop products. In short, my vision for the creation of a cyborg design system will remove self-imposed informational constraints, allowing human designers to efficiently focus on what they’re best at: creating the world around us.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Identifying Technical and Economic Improvements to the MoneyMaker Hip Pump through Multi-Objective Optimization</title>
   <link href="http://www.cmccomb.com/publications/2015/McCombetal-IdentifyingTechnicalAndEconomic/"/>
   <updated>2015-01-01T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://www.cmccomb.com/publications/2015/McCombetal-IdentifyingTechnicalAndEconomic</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Water-lifting technologies in rural areas of the developing world have enormous potential to stimulate agricultural production and economic growth. The MoneyMaker Hip pump designed by Kickstart is a human-powered low cost pump, which can help subsistence farmers increase financial returns. This work optimizes the design of the MoneyMaker Hip pump, which is the cheapest and lightest portable water pump from Kickstart. A mathematical model of the working fluid and MoneyMaker Hip pump structure is developed. Deterministic optimization methods are then employed to maximize the flow rate of the groundwater pumped, maximize the lift height, and minimize the volume of material used for manufacturing. Design variables for the optimization included the dimensions of the pump, well depth, and speed of various parts of the system. The solutions are subject to constraints on the geometry of the system, the bending stress in the handle and cylinder, and ergonomic factors. Findings indicate that several technical improvements can be made on the current MoneyMaker Hip pump design to reduce the cost and human workload.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Enhancing Shear Transfer in Composite Decks</title>
   <link href="http://www.cmccomb.com/publications/2015/McCombTehrani-EnhancementofShearTransfer/"/>
   <updated>2015-01-01T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://www.cmccomb.com/publications/2015/McCombTehrani-EnhancementofShearTransfer</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Reinforced concrete construction and steel construction are two of the most common contemporary construction methods. Both methods make use of composite decks as floor systems and diaphragms. During the design of composite decks, the interaction between the steel deck and concrete slab is typically disregarded when calculating the strength of the composite diaphragm due to lack of complete shear transfer, as existing practices such as stamping are not effective to provide substantial composite action. This conservative assumption essentially results in non-efficient use of material. This paper presents a method for ensuring shear transfer through the use of conventional sheet metal screws, driven through the corrugated steel deck and embedded in the fresh concrete. This method is proposed for use in the field between formed steel beams. Both experimental and analytical studies support an increase in strength with the addition of embedded fasteners. Further, experimental results indicate an additional increase in strength with the addition of synthetic reinforcing fibers. The increase in strength with the addition of the fasteners is on the order of 100%. When fasteners are already in use, the addition of synthetic reinforcing fibers can increase strength on the order of 10%. The ultimate deflection of enhanced deck is comparable to deck tested without fasteners, but the initial stiffness of enhanced deck is much higher.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Studying Human Design Teams through Computational Teams of Simulated Annealing Agents</title>
   <link href="http://www.cmccomb.com/publications/2015/McCombCaganKotovsky-StudyingHumanDesignTeams/"/>
   <updated>2015-01-01T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://www.cmccomb.com/publications/2015/McCombCaganKotovsky-StudyingHumanDesignTeams</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Novel design methodologies are often evaluated through empirical studies involving human designers. However, such empirical studies can incur a high personnel cost. Further, it can be difficult to isolate the effects of specific team or individual characteristics. These limitations could be bypassed by employing a computational model of design teams. This work introduces the Cognitively-Inspired Simulated Annealing Teams (CISAT) modeling framework, an agent-based platform that provides a means for efficiently simulating human design teams. A number of empirically demonstrated cognitive phenomena are modeled within the platform, striking a balance between model simplicity and direct applicability to engineering design problems. This paper discusses the composition of the CISAT modeling framework and demonstrates how it can be used to simulate the performance of human design teams in a cognitive study. Results simulated with CISAT are compared directly to the results derived from human designers. Finally, the CISAT model is also used to investigate the characteristics that were most and least helpful to teams during the cognitive study.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Rolling with the Punches: An Examination of Team Performance in a Design Task Subject to Drastic Changes</title>
   <link href="http://www.cmccomb.com/publications/2015/McCombCaganKotovsky-RollingWithThePunches/"/>
   <updated>2015-01-01T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://www.cmccomb.com/publications/2015/McCombCaganKotovsky-RollingWithThePunches</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Designers must often create solutions to problems that exhibit dynamic characteristics. For instance, a client might modify specifications after design has commenced, or a competitor may introduce a new technology or feature. This paper presents a cognitive study that was conducted to explore the manner in which design teams respond to such situations. In the study, teams of undergraduate engineering students sought to solve a design task that was subject to two large, unexpected changes in problem formulation that were introduced during solving. High- and low-performing teams demonstrated very different approaches to solving the problem and overcoming the changes. The results indicate that there may exist a relationship between problem characteristics and fruitful solution strategies.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Lifting the Veil: Drawing insights about design teams from a cognitively-inspired computational model</title>
   <link href="http://www.cmccomb.com/publications/2015/McCombCaganKotovsky-LiftingTheVeil/"/>
   <updated>2015-01-01T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://www.cmccomb.com/publications/2015/McCombCaganKotovsky-LiftingTheVeil</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Novel design methodologies are often evaluated through studies involving human designers, but such studies can incur a high personnel cost. It can also be difficult to isolate the effects of specific team or individual characteristics. This work introduces the Cognitively-Inspired Simulated Annealing Teams (CISAT) modeling framework, a platform for efficiently simulating and analyzing human design teams. The framework models a number of empirically demonstrated cognitive phenomena, thus balancing simplicity and direct applicability. This paper discusses the model’s composition, and demonstrates its utility through simulating human design teams in a cognitive study. Simulation results are compared directly to the results from human designers. The CISAT model is also used to identify the most beneficial characteristics in the cognitive study.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Improving Irrigation in Remote Areas: Multi-objective Optimization of a Treadle Pump</title>
   <link href="http://www.cmccomb.com/publications/2014/SantaeufemiaJohnsonMcCombShimada-ImprovingIrrigationInRemote/"/>
   <updated>2014-10-01T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://www.cmccomb.com/publications/2014/SantaeufemiaJohnsonMcCombShimada-ImprovingIrrigationInRemote</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Water-lifting technologies in rural areas of the developing world have enormous potential to stimulate agricultural and economic growth. The treadle pump, a human-powered low-cost pump designed for irrigation in developing countries, can help farmers maximize financial return on small plots of land by ending their dependency on rain-fed irrigation systems. The treadle pump uses a suction piston to draw groundwater to the surface by way of a foot-powered treadle attached to each suction piston. Current treadle pump designs lift water from depths up to 7 meters at a flow-rate of 1–5 liters per second. This work seeks to optimize the design of the Dekhi style treadle pump, which has gained significant popularity due to its simplicity. A mathematical model of the working fluid and treadle pump structure has been developed in this study. Deterministic optimization methods are then employed to maximize the flow rate of the groundwater pumped, maximize the lift height, and minimize the volume of material used for manufacturing. Design variables for the optimization included the dimensions of the pump, well depth, and speed of various parts of the system. The solutions are subject to constraints on the geometry of the system, the bending stress in the treadles, and ergonomic factors. Findings indicate that significant technical improvements can be made on the standard Dekhi design, such as increasing the size of the pump cylinders and hose, while maintaining a standard total treadle length. These improvements could allow the Dekhi pump to be implemented in new regions and benefit additional rural farmers in the developing world.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Quantitative Comparison of High- and Low-Performing Teams in a Design Task Subject to Drastic Changes</title>
   <link href="http://www.cmccomb.com/publications/2014/McCombCaganKotovsky-QuantitativeComparisonOfHigh/"/>
   <updated>2014-08-01T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://www.cmccomb.com/publications/2014/McCombCaganKotovsky-QuantitativeComparisonOfHigh</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Many design tasks are subject to changes in goals or constraints. For instance, a client might modify specifications after design has commenced, or a competitor may introduce a new technology or feature. A design team often cannot anticipate such changes, yet they pose a considerable challenge. This paper presents a study where engineering teams sought to solve a design task that was subject to two large, unexpected changes in problem formulation that occurred during problem solving. Continuous design data was collected to observe how the designers responded to the changes. We show that high- and low-performing teams demonstrated very different approaches to solving the problem and overcoming the changes. In particular, high-performing teams achieved simple designs and extensively explored small portions of the design space; low-performing teams explored complex designs with little exploration around a target area of the design space. These strategic differences are interpreted with respect to cognitive load theory and goal theory. The results raise questions as to the relationship between characteristics of design problems and solution strategies. In addition, an attempt at increasing the teams’ resilience in the face of unexpected changes is introduced by encouraging early divergent search.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Research and Practice Group Methodology: A Case Study in Student Success.</title>
   <link href="http://www.cmccomb.com/publications/2014/McCombTehrani-ResearchAndPracticeGroup/"/>
   <updated>2014-04-01T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://www.cmccomb.com/publications/2014/McCombTehrani-ResearchAndPracticeGroup</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Experiential learning is a key component in engineering education. In civil engineering, this component is typically delivered through multiple projects. These projects may include term projects for individual courses, senior design projects, theses, or independent studies. The focus of these experiences may gradually shift from practice-oriented projects in undergraduate studies to research-oriented projects in graduate studies. Thus, learning objectives should always address both areas with a strong emphasis on common fields, such as applied research. Experiential learning has the capacity to include various program-level outcomes, such as technical knowledge, communication and teamwork. Development of a research and practice group facilitates these outcomes by creating an environment to share the learning experience. Such a group should replicate the working environment of civil engineers by incorporating multidisciplinary projects and diverse individuals, including cross-generational members. As a case study, this work examines a Research and Practice Group at California State University Fresno. This group consists of junior and senior undergraduates, graduate students, and former members who are participating as alumni. The major focus of research within the group is resilient and sustainable structural mechanics and design. This paper outlines the methodology that has been employed to ensure academic and professional success for members of the group. This methodology incorporates a recruitment process, meetings, consultation, mentorship, networking, and support. The level of student success achieved by the group is presented in terms of the achievements of the group’s members. This includes a discussion of completed projects, research funding, and group presentations. To further demonstrate the efficacy of the methodology, students in the research group are compared to the general body of engineering students at CSU Fresno though the results of a survey. This survey is analyzed using traditional methods, as well as Latent Semantic Analysis. Our results indicate that group members are better at embodying and communicating outcomes than the rest of the student body, and that the research and practice group provides an experience that allows students to internalize and take responsibility for their own goals.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Development and Verification of a Wave Energy Converter Simulation Tool</title>
   <link href="http://www.cmccomb.com/publications/2013/McCombLawsonYu-DevelopmentAndVerification/"/>
   <updated>2013-04-01T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://www.cmccomb.com/publications/2013/McCombLawsonYu-DevelopmentAndVerification</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Numerical simulations to predict the dynamics and performance of wave energy converters (WECs) are challenging, requiring the simulation of complex fluid-structure interactions between a WEC device and the wave environment. Full Navier-Stokes computational fluid dynamics (CFD) simulations coupled with a multi-body dynamics solver are an effective simulation tool for this purpose because the governing physics are modeled from first physical principles. Unfortunately, the computational resources required to perform these types of high-fidelity simulations are significant, precluding the use of CFD simulations for design optimization. One method for reducing the numerical complexity of WEC simulations is to model the hydrodynamics using a heuristic approach that uses hydrodynamic coefficients derived from frequency-domain simulations to model the relevant hydrodynamics, while simulating the motion of the WEC device in the time-domain. The primary objective of the work presented herein is to develop such a numerical tool using the multi-body 6-degree-of-freedom (6DOF) solver SimMechanics and the frequency-domain hydrodynamics code WAMIT. The numerical tool was developed so that WEC devices comprised of arbitrarily connected multiple bodies and various power-take-off (PTO) systems could be readily modeled in operational sea states. In addition, the tool was developed to allow non-linear PTO control strategies to be considered. Using the simulation tool described above, the effect of fluid memory on predicted power output is then investigated. This is accomplished through comparison of numerical results with and without fluid memory.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Enhancement of Concrete Composite Decks</title>
   <link href="http://www.cmccomb.com/publications/2012/EnhancementOfConcreteComposite/"/>
   <updated>2012-05-01T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://www.cmccomb.com/publications/2012/EnhancementOfConcreteComposite</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Reinforced concrete construction and steel construction are two of the most common contemporary construction methods. Both methods make use of composite decks as floor systems and diaphragms. During the design of composite decks, the steel deck is typically disregarded when calculating the strength of the slab since shear transfer can’t be ensured. This essentially results in efficient use of material. This report presents a method for ensuring shear transfer through the use of typical sheet metal screws, driven through the corrugated steel deck and embedded in the concrete. Both experimental and analytical work support an increase in strength with the addition of embedded fasteners, and an increase in strength with the addition of synthetic reinforcing fibers.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 

</feed>
